Guide to the Bernice Hopkins papers, 1925-1999.
Hopkins, Bernice papers, 1925-1999
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bernice Hopkins papers, 1925-1999.
23-3-3128
Bernice Margaret Hopkins 1907-
2.7 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, articles, photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, recipes, awards, articles, photographs, memorabilia, and other records of Bernice Hopkins as a student in Institution Management at Cornell, a dietitian, a lecturer in the Division of Nutritional Science at Cornell University and her work as a volunteer at Footnet.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Class of 1932.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, recipes, awards, articles, photographs, memorabilia, and other records of Bernice Hopkins as a student in Institution Management at Cornell, a dietitian, a lecturer in the Division of Nutritional Science at Cornell University and her work as a volunteer at Footnet.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hopkins, Bernice Margaret,1907-; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Class of 1932.; Foodnet (Ithaca, N.Y.); New York State College of Home Economics.; New York State College of Home Economics.Dept. of Institution Management.; New York State College of Human Ecology.
Subjects:
Dietitians.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
  - The Sandborn Descendents - Genealogy, 1899-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters of Recognition, Biography, Misc. Memorabilia of Bernice Hopkins, 1933-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bernice Hopkins-Personal, 1981-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History of the Department of Institution of Management by Bernice Hopkins, 1925-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Guatemala, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Information/ History/ Correspondence about Home Economics/ Human Ecology at Cornell, 1963-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History of Manhattan Management and Related Correspondence, 1998-11-13 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kilimanjaro Tale-The Saga of a Medical Family in Africa, by Gwnneth Latham (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dom Econ Cake Recipe, The Cook's Assistant, Deerfield Fair Cookbooks, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - (Removed from) "My Favorite Recipes" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Muddy Pond Mennonite Community Cookbook (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stones River Medical Community Cookbook, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Recipe Book (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Two Small Recipe Books (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Recipe Books (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - FoodNet Retirement Certificate, Carrol College Recognition Certificate-both removed from frames, 1999, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Army Certificate of Service, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Senior Citizen of the Year Award, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - New York State Award for Improving the Life of Senior Citizens, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Senior Citizen Outstanding Contribution, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Course Completion Certificate for Army, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Four portraits of Bernice Hopkins including Senior Portraits, 1925, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Portrait of Orvis Hopkins, Baby Portrait (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Girl Graduate's Record Book from Bernice's Senior year of High School, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Senior Class Portrait Book, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Items saved by Bernice Hopkins (articles, pamphlets, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Photocopies of articles saved by Bernice Hopkins (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Articles and letters (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Articles and letters (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Portrait of young girl (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Seven small photos including Bernice Hopkins around age two (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Two mounted portraits of Bernice Hopkins -various ages (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Three photos of Bernice Hopkins -various ages (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Three portraits of Bernice Hopkins as a child/ baby (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Two portraits including Bernice Hopkins (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - New York State College of Human Ecology at Cornell University Certificate of Recognition to Bernice Hopkins - Board Member Emeritus, 1989-06-09 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Rotary Foundation names Bernice Hopkins a Paul Harris Fellow - certificate, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Ithaca Sunrise Rotary Club - Bernice Hopkins - Honorary Rotarian plaque, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Metal box of recipes from the United States Navy (Box 2)
  - VUMC Dietetic Internship Director-gold plate, 1949-1960 (Box 2)
  - Brenice Hopkins-Retired from the New York State College of Human Ecology at Cornell University - Silver Plate, 1974-06-19 (Box 2)
  - Bernice Hopkins - The American Dietetic Association - glass plaque (Box 2)
  - Paul Harris Fellow medal (Box 2)
  - Envelope of various name badges and ribbons for Bernice Hopkins (Box 2)
  - Slide show-"Planning your Community Kitchen-A Cornell Slide Set" (Box 2)
  - Lace knitted by B.H.'s Grandmother, 1955-1959 (Box 2)
  - Lace knitted by B.H.'s Aunt Carrie, 1955-1959 (Box 2)
  - Pink and white flowered bag "Ditty Bag." Note by Bernice Hopkins - given me by 'Red Cross' when I went overseas in 1945. It had many things, a pocket book (to read) comb toothpaste -etc, things an overseas military person could use.", 1955-1959 (Box 2)
  - 2 cream colored towels. Note by Bernice Hopkins -"These towels were wedding presents to my father and mother-They were married October 10, I think, 1906." Note by B.H., 1955-1959 (Box 2)
  - Pink lacy jacket. Note by Bernice Hopkins - "I left the Panama Canal Zone in 1945 after 11 years. The daughter of our 'clerk' in the dietary department made this jacket for me. -To this day it has never been worn. De Dier (clerk) was from Martinique-an extremely intelligent, helpful person." (Box 2)
  - Red beret witha 32 patch on it. (Box 2)
  - Wooden keepsake box with two compartments. Non-paper items have been left in the box. Folders 22-31 in Box 2 contain paper items removed from it. (Box 3)
  - Mounted portrait of Bernice Hopkins in Army Uniform (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Army Medical Center Junior Dietitians Course Completion Certificate, 1933-06-29 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Bernice Hopkins' Bachelor of Science Diploma from Cornell University (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Helen Bull Vandervort -Human Ecology Alumni Achievement Award, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Tompkins County Trust Co. Award for Excellence, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reunion material for the class of 1932, including the commencement program, 1982-1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Recognition of being a member of the American Dietetic Association for fifty years, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Biographical file - letters, articles, resume (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Association Constitutions and Bylaws, 1950-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Various memos concerning the College of Human Ecology (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences - memos, 1980-1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Passports (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Certificates from the College of Human Ecology Alumni Association
  - Photos of quilts made by the Bliss and Van Alstyne Families in the mid 1800s